Grab life by the ball.
DodgeBall: A True Underdog Story is a comedy film
directed by Rawson Marshall Thurber.
When megalomaniacal White Goodman, the owner of a trendy, high-end fitness center, makes a move to take over the struggling
local gym run by happy-go-lucky Pete La Fleur, there's only one way for La Fleur to fight back: dodgeball.
Aided by a dodgeball guru and Goodman's attorney, La Fleur and his rag-tag team of
underdogs launch a knock-down, drag-out battle in which the winner takes all.
Peter La Fleur, played by Vince Vaughn.
Kate Veatch, played by Christine Taylor.
White Goodman, played by Ben Stiller.
Patches O'Houlihan, played by Rip Torn.
Justin, played by Justin Long.
Gordon, played by Stephen Root.
Dodgeball: A True Underdog Story (stylized as DodgeBall: A True Underdog Story) is a 2004 sports comedy film written and
directed by Rawson Marshall Thurber and starring Vince Vaughn, Ben Stiller, Christine Taylor, and Rip Torn.
The film follows a group of unlikely misfits who enter a Las Vegas dodgeball tournament, needing the prize
money to save their cherished gym from being taken over by a corporate health fitness chain.
Theatrically released by 20th Century Fox on June 18, 2004, the film received generally
positive reviews from critics and grossed $168.4 million on a $20 million budget.
As of 2023, a sequel was in development.
The film explores themes of underdog, sports, love at
first sight, competition, gymnasium.
The tone is lighthearted.